Guide to the Anthony Weir Papers, 1954-2006 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Anthony Weir papers 1954-1996 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Weir, Anthony
4.7 linear feet Extent: 2,625 Items
Anthony Weir is a marketing communications executive with the Whitford Corporation and runs Weir Marketing Communications. He started his career as a copywriter for Batten, Barton, Durstine, and Osborn (BBDO), then worked as a specialist in starting up and managing offices in Asia and Latin America for the Ogilvy & Mather and Leo Burnett advertising agencies. The Anthony Weir Papers span the years 1954 through 2006 and include advertising copy, brochures, clippings, memoranda, correspondence, photographs, and slides representing Weir's advertising career, especially his work for BBDO and Ogilvy & Mather (O&M). Clients mentioned in the collection include the Lever Brothers, Hertz, Sears, Owens-Corning, American Express, and Schweppes. The collection also contains correspondence and clippings about Anthony's father, Walter Weir, also a marketing executive; and documents from the files of Jane Maas, Weir's colleague at Ogilvy.
RL.01361
Language: Material is in English and Spanish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Anthony Weir Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2003.
Biographical Note
1936 May 3 Born in Langhorne, PA
1958 AB English, Duke University
1959 Mar. Copywriter, Batton, Barton, Durstine, & Osborn Inc.
1962 Copywriter, Ogilvy & Mather (O&M) New York
circa 1963 Vice-President, O&M New York
circa 1964 Copy Group Head, O&M New York
1965 Senior Vice-President and Creative Director, O&M New York
1974 Managing Director of CORPA Publicidad, O&M Venezuela
1978 Regional Coordinator of Latin America and Director General of O&M Mexico
1983 Director General of Latin America and O&M Mexico
1985 Senior Vice-President, Group Account Director, Council of Directors, O&M Worldwide
1986 Managing Director, Euramerica International Advertising, a division of O&M Worldwide
1987 Managing Director of Hong Kong office and Asia, Leo Burnett Asia
1989 Managing Director, Leo Burnett Argentina
1991 Director/Shareholder, Director of Worldwide Communications, Whitford Corporation
1996 President, Weir Marketing Communications
Collection Overview
The Anthony Weir Papers span the years 1954 through 2006 and include advertising copy, brochures, clippings, memoranda, correspondence, photographs, and slides representing Weir's advertising career, especially his work for Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn (BBDO) and Ogilvy & Mather. Clients mentioned in the collection include the Lever Brothers, Hertz, Sears, Owens-Corning, American Express, and Schweppes. The collection also contains correspondence and clippings about Anthony's father, Walter Weir, also a marketing executive; and documents from the files of Jane Maas, Weir's colleague at Ogilvy.
The collection is organized into six series: Personal, Client Files, Jane Maas, Other Professional Materials, Writings, Slides, and Oversize Materials. The Personal Series contains biographical data about Weir and his family and friends through correspondence, clippings, greeting cards, photographs, and identification documents. The Client Files Series documents Weir's advertising accounts at Ogilvy & Mather. The Jane Maas Series consists of papers from the files of Weir's colleague at Ogilvy & Mather. The Other Professional Materials Series represents advertising work not directly related to Weir's tenure at Ogilvy & Mather. The Writings Series includes Weir's published and unpublished creative and professional writings. The Slides Series consists of slide images related to the advertising campaigns that Weir worked on for his clients. Large-format print materials have been removed from their original series locations and relocated to Oversize Materials. Relocated items have been indicated in the Detailed Description of the Collection by notes enclosed in brackets.
Subject Headings
Weir, Anthony, 1936-; Maas, Jane; Weir, Walter; Ogilvy & Mather; Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn, Inc.; Lever Brothers Company; Hertz Corporation; Sears, Roebuck and Company; Owens-Corning Fiberglas Corporation; American Express Company; Schweppes (Firm); Advertising copy; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- United States; Marketing; Slides; Clippings; Memoranda; Brochures; Photographs
Related Material
Materials related to those contained in this collection may be found in other Hartman Center collections, including the Walter Weir Papers, 1909-1996, bulk 1950-1990; the J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Records, 1978-2000 and undated; the Arthur Einstein Papers, circa 1990-2001; the J. Walter Thompson Company. Thomas Sutton Papers, 1965-1975 and undated; the J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporation Vertical Files, circa 1915-1999, bulk 1960s-1990s; and the Wells, Rich, Greene, Inc. Records.
Contents of Collection
- Personal Series, 1936-1970 and undated, 1 Box
  Contains clippings, correspondence, family photographs, identification cards, greeting cards, and other personal documents. Arranged alphabetically.
  - An Open Letter to Agency Presidents, circa 1960 (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1963-1979 (some items in Spanish) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1993 and undated (Box 1)
  - Family photographs and greeting cards, 1965-1970 and undated (Box 1)
  - Personal identification documents, 1954-1964 and undated (Box 1)
  - Resumes, circa 1960 (Box 1)
- Writings Series, circa 1959-2006, 1 Box (Box 1)
  Contains published copies and unpublished manuscripts of poetry, prose and non-fiction written by Weir. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Get Me The White House! co-authored with Jacques Kelly, 2006 (Box 1)
    Subtitle of the book reads The untold story of Victor Frankil's rise from immigrant obscurity to prominence in the turbulent worlds of business and politics.
  - How to Brief Your Advertising Agency, circa 1984 (Box 1)
  - Loose poems and prose, circa 1959 (Box 1)
  - The Whitford Guide to Corporate Communications, 2002 (Box 1)
- Client Files Series, 1967-1986 and undated, (5 Boxes) (Box 1)
  Includes memoranda, clippings, correspondence, and drafts of advertising copy from campaigns Weir worked on while at Ogilvy & Mather. Arranged alphabetically.
  - American Express, Money Card, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - General Foods, Maxim, 1967-1970, (1-4 of 16 folders) (Box 1)
    [Some items removed to Oversize Materials, Box 9]
  - General Foods, Maxim, 1967-1970 (continued), (5-14 of 16 folders) (Box 2)
  - General Foods, Maxim, 1967-1970 (continued), (15-16 of 16 folders) (Box 3)
  - Hertz International Inc., 1967-1970, (9 folders) (Box 3)
  - Junior Achievement, Inc., Junior Achievement, 1972-1973 and undated, (3 folders) (Box 4)
  - Lever Brothers Company, Dove soap, 1968-1970, (7 folders) (Box 4)
  - Menley & James, Contac, 1969-1971, (1-2 of 5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Menley & James, Contac, 1969-1971 (continued), (3-5 of 5 folders) (Box 5)
  - NYC Parks, Recreation & Cultural Affairs Administration, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Owens-Corning Fiberglas Corporation, decorative and home furnishings, 1970-1972, (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Polyarch, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Sears, Color TV, 1972-1973 and undated (Box 5)
  - Sears, Excalibur, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
  - Sears, Hangups, 1971 (Box 5)
- Jane Maas Files Series, 1967-1973 and undated, 1 Box (Box 5)
  Includes correspondence, clippings, brochures, memoranda, and advertising copy from the files of Weir's colleague at Ogilvy & Mather, Jane Maas. Maas is best known for her work at the Wells, Rich, Greene agency, where she directed the I Love New York advertising campaign that helped revitalize New York City's tourism economy. Maas left Ogilvy & Mather to work for Wells, Rich, Greene in 1976. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Burpee, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence from Hap, undated (Box 6)
  - How To Tell It Like It Is, District publicist's kit, Girl Scout Council of Greater New York, Inc., 1972 (Box 6)
  - Merrill Lynch, undated (Box 6)
  - Ogilvy & Mather Foundation, 1967-1973 (Box 6)
  - Owens-Corning Fiberglas industry competitive advertisements, 1972 (Box 6)
  - The Heads Together/Officer's Committee Handbook, 1972 (Box 6)
- Other Professional Materials Series, 1960-1973 and undated, 1 Box (Box 6)
  Includes memoranda, brochures, presentations, advertisement clippings, and loose advertising copy by Weir. Arranged alphabetically.
  - All Type, copy clinic file, 1960-1967 (Box 6)
    [Items removed to Oversize Materials, Box 9]
  - Babies, copy clinic file, 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Big Job on a Little Budget, undated (Box 6)
  - Cartoons, copy clinic file, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
    [Iems removed to Oversize Materials, Box 9]
  - Clippings, circa 1965 and 1970-1972 (Box 6)
  - Competitive Advertisements, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - Contest, Bristol-Myers Company, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Coupon Ads, copy clinic file, 1965-1966 and undated (Box 6)
  - Doesn't Everybody? Mackinac Island speech by Whit Hobbs, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Egregious Advertising, 1967-1968 (Box 6)
  - House Advertising, copy clinic file, 1964-1969 (Box 6)
  - Media Advertising, copy clinic file, 1961-1966 (Box 6)
  - Multi-Illustrations, copy clinic file, 1964-1965 (Box 6)
  - Ogilvy & Mather memoranda, 1963-1973, bulk 1973 (Box 6)
  - Old Bromide True As Ever, circa 1964 (Box 6)
  - Reader Involvement, copy clinic file, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - Small Space, copy clinic file, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Special Events, copy clinic file, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - The Evolution of American Advertising, presented by William D. Tyler, Unilever Conference on Creative Advertising Principles, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Tigers, copy clinic file, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
  - What Consumerism Means for Marketers, by Philip Kotler, Harvard Business Review, 1972 (Box 6)
- Slides Series, 1969-1973 and undated, 2 Boxes (Box 6)
  Includes color slides of advertising commercial shots for various clients and products. Arranged Chronologically
  - 1969 Dec., Schweppes, seashore, Nov. 1969, (3 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1970 Jan., Schweppes, 12/69, demolition, telephone kiosk, Pat R. (Box 7)
  - 1970 Jan., Schweppes, 12/69, demolition, baronial hall, Elsbeth (Box 7)
  - 1970 Jan., Schweppes, 12/69, demolition exteriors (Box 7)
  - 1970 Jan., Schweppes, 12/69, demolition, interiors (Box 7)
  - 1970 Jan., Schweppes, 12/69, telephone booth, Xmas-Newtown (Box 7)
  - 1970 Mar., IP Paper Bridge, 2/70 (Box 7)
  - 1970 Mar., IP Paper Bridge, 2/70, Tim and Matthew (Box 7)
  - 1970 Mar., JP Paper Bridge, 2/70 (Box 7)
  - 1970 Mar., JP Paper Bridge, 2/70, Bren Company (Box 7)
  - 1970 May, Acapulco (Box 7)
  - 1970 May, Acapulco, Warren Marcus, New Haven (Box 7)
  - 1970 May, Sint Maarten (Box 7)
  - 1970 May, Sint Maarten 4/70, Acapulco 5/70 (Box 7)
  - 1970 Sep., Penelope, England, (2 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1972 Jun., Maxim, Big Joe and Willis, WKND, March (Box 7)
  - 1972 Aug., Money Card, July, Wyoming, Mexico City (Box 7)
  - 1972 Aug., Mexico City and Washington (Box 7)
  - 1972 Aug., Washington and Miami (Box 7)
  - 1972 Sep., Munich August 1972 (Box 7)
  - 1972 Sep., Rome 8/72 (Box 7)
  - 1972 Sep., Rome, London, Wiltshire (Box 7)
  - 1972 Oct., East Grinstead Seltzer, 9/72 (Box 7)
  - 1972 Oct., New York, Rockefeller Center, Serial (Box 7)
  - 1972 Oct., New York, Serial (Box 7)
  - 1973 Mar., Sydney, TW Office (Box 8)
  - 1973 Mar., Sydney (Box 8)
  - 1973 May, Australia, April-May, Lindifferon, Mandy Beach, Dave and Bronvyn (Box 8)
  - 1973 May, Australia, April-May, Norfolk St., Dave and Bronvyn in Sydney (Box 8)
  - 1973 May, Australia, April-May, Provender, Sailing, Norfolk St. (Box 8)
  - 1973 May, Australia, April-May, Sailing, Lindifferon (Box 8)
  - Undated, IP, Ga. (Box 8)
  - Undated, IP and Kids (Box 8)
  - Undated, Negatives (Box 8)
- Oversize Materials, (1 Box) (Box 8)
  - Client Files Series (Box 8)
    - General Foods, Maxim, 1967-1970, (16 folders) (Box 9)
  - Other Professional Materials (Box 9)
    - All Type, copy clinic file, 1960-1966 (Box 9)
    - Babies, copy clinic file, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
    - Cartoons, copy clinic file, 1964-1966 (Box 9)
    - House advertising, copy clinic file, 1964-1969 (Box 9)
    - Media advertising, copy clinic file, 1961-1966 (Box 9)
    - Multi-illustrations, copy clinic file, 1964-1965 (Box 9)
    - Reader involvement, copy clinic file, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
    - Special events, copy clinic file, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
    - Tigers, copy clinic file, 1964-1966 (Box 9)